<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>com.airtame.Client</id>
  <name>Airtame</name>
  <summary>Interact wirelessly with your shared screens in seconds</summary>
  <developer id="com.airtame">
      <name>Airtame</name>
  </developer>
  <description>
  <p>Revolutionize the way you connect, communicate, and collaborate with Airtame. The user-friendly solution enhancing productivity and engagement, in any environment inside your school or business.</p>
  <p>NOTE: This wrapper is not verified by, affiliated with, or supported by Airtame Inc.</p>
</description>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>LicenseRef-proprietary</project_license>
  <url type="help">https://help.airtame.com/</url>
  <url type="homepage">https://airtame.com/</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://dashboard.snapcraft.io/site_media/appmedia/2020/04/Take_control.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://dashboard.snapcraft.io/site_media/appmedia/2020/04/Share_together_1_1.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <categories>
    <category>Utility</category>
  </categories>
  <!-- https://changelog.airtame.com/en?category=airtame+app</url> -->
  <releases>
    <release version="4.14.0" date="2025-07-30">
      <description></description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.13.1" date="2025-05-07">
      <description/>
    </release>
    <release version="4.12.0" date="2024-12-02">
      <description/>
    </release>
    <release version="4.11.0" date="2024-09-10">
      <description/>
    </release>
    <release version="4.10.0" date="2024-04-23">
      <description>
        <p>New features</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Conferencing: Screen sharing into video calls with audio from Mac, when you are hosting the call</li>
          </ul>
        <p>Bug fixes</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Conferencing: Mouse curser might duplicate on Windows while screensharing into calls</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.5.3" date="2022-08-12"/>
    <release version="4.5.2" date="2022-09-13">
      <description>
        <p>Bug fixes</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Fixed an issue where devices on Firmware version 3.5.1 could no longer be set up using the Airtame application</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.5.0" date="2022-09-06">
      <description>
        <p>New features</p>
          <ul>
            <li>802.1X authentication for ethernet added in setup flow and device settings</li>
            <li>Rooms: Sign in with Google Calendar to have easier access to your meetings</li>
            <li>Rooms: Added the ability to join calls on Linux</li>
          </ul>
        <p>Improvements</p>
          <ul>
            <li>New streaming technology for Linux: WebRTC-based streaming to provide a smoother screen sharing experience and the ability to select which screen to share in multi-screen setups. This also adds support for the latest Ubuntu LTS version</li>
            <li>Audio on Linux is for the moment no longer supported. We will seek to add audio at a later date. Customers who wish to use audio streaming on Linux should stay on app version 4.1.1</li>
            <li>Added new security controls following Electron best practices, including but not limited to the prevention of untrusted resources</li>
          </ul>
        <p>Bug fixes</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Rooms: Fixed an issue that prevented sharing a single window to a Teams call when two overlapping windows of the same program are present, e.g. during a PowerPoint presentation</li>
            <li>Rooms: Fixed an issue that prevented sharing content from a secondary monitor to a Teams call</li>
            <li>Rooms: Cancelling a request to join a call in the Airtame application should now properly return the Airtame Hub to an idle state</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.2.1" date="2021-07-05">
      <description>
        <p>Bug fixes</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Fixed an issue where the app would crash when attempting to stream to an offline device</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.2.0" date="2021-06-07">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Streaming via the Airtame app (native Airtame protocol) now utilizes TCP as a transport layer protocol instead of ENET on UDP. This should lead to increased performance when screen sharing, in particular during video playback</li>
          </ul>
        <p>Bug fixes</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Fixed the issue when a stream would not start from a source device with an odd resolution (e.g. 1904x949)</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.1.1" date="2020-08-17">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Allow analytics to use system proxy</li>
            <li>Improve the analytics retry mechanism (in case an analytics event failed to be sent)</li>
          </ul>
        <p>Bug fixes</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Fix for the missing tray icon on Windows when dark mode is enabled for applications</li>
            <li>Fix for the app getting stuck in the Setup Flow when trying to connect to a device</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.1.0" date="2020-06-30">
      <description>
        <p>New features</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Additional security step during setup flow: users can choose to set a password for the Airtame's Access Point and its settings during the setup flow. They can skip the step and configure this later, if they wish. </li>
            <li>Do Not Disturb functionality on macOS while streaming: users can opt-out of this functionality in the Preferences menu fo the App. </li>
          </ul>
        <p>Improvements</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Search results have been improved to better match multiple search terms.</li>
            <li>UI and text changes for the "Not able to find this device" screen.</li>
            <li>UI and text changes for the setup flow confirmation step.</li>
          </ul>
        <p>Bug fixes</p>
          <ul>
            <li>MSI starting at system startup even though the installer was invoked with WRAPPED_ARGUMENTS="/autostart=false".</li>
            <li>Setup flow logic sometimes not recognising it has successfully connected to the Airtame device.</li>
            <li>Setup flow failing on non-English OS versions.</li>
            <li>Non-admin macOS users failing to start the application.</li>
            <li>Broken UI when window picking fails because the window cannot be shared (for instance Task Manager window).</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.0.1" date="2020-05-12">
      <description>
        <p>Issues fixed:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed expired signing certificate on Windows app</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.0.0" date="2020-03-24">
      <description>
        <p>New features</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The application can be minimised/maximised to/from task bar, moved around the screen(s) and resized vertically.</li>
          <li>SoundFlower kernel extension was replaced with Airtame Audio driver for Mac.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Cross-VLAN support for mDNS.</li>
          <li>The application opens minimised on system startup.</li>
          <li>The application will only show existing devices while searching (better support for connect via IP or DNS name).</li>
          <li>Use white tray icon on Mac dark mode and Linux.</li>
          <li>UI changes to streaming notification.</li>
          <li>UI changes to Setup Flow and Device Settings.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Issues fixed</p>
        <ul>
          <li>3.6.1 MSI returning 1603 error code.</li>
          <li>Windows Guest app looking for new updates.</li>
          <li>MSI application start on user login if MSI installer was invoked with WRAPPED_ARGUMENTS="/autostart=true".</li>
          <li>Favourite devices update the IP address on discovery: if Airtame marked as "Favourite" has changed the IP, the user will be able to access it through the app without having to re-favourite it.</li>
          <li>Setup flow configuring WiFi network when ethernet setup was selected.</li>
          <li>Pincode not getting focus on touch devices having the keyboard layout in a foreign language (e.g. French).</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.6.1" date="2019-11-26">
      <description>
        <p>Fix for macOS Catalina to accommodate for new flow for getting screen recording permissions.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.6.0" date="2019-11-14">
      <description>
        <p>New features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>MacOS Catalina flow for approving video recording and microphone access.</li>
          <li>UI changes of device resolutions in Airtame Settings menu (warnings if current resolution doesn't match the configured resolution and warnings if EDID read failed).</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Issues fixed:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Improvements to the Airtame app search functionality.</li>
          <li>Improvements to the streamer module: New WASAPI implementation for Windows (sound capture). </li>
          <li>General bug fixes; Mouse cursor drawing for Single Window Sharing on Windows;</li>
          <li>Single Windows Sharing scaling bug fix.</li>
          <li>Disable audio button while streaming if Airtame resolution doesn't support audio.</li>
          <li>Change Ubuntu snap confinement to "strict" so we can publish in Ubuntu store: This means that Linux application won't detect unconfigured/oob devices anymore, but setup will have to be through the manual setup flow.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Important bug fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix the issue when Airtame app sometimes couldn't reconnect to Airtame.</li>
          <li>Fix for on-screen keyboard not showing up on PIN code on touch devices.</li>
          <li>Fix for disconnecting the stream when pressing 'Enter' key after filling in the PIN code.</li>
          <li>Fix for Airtame app moving outside of screen after streaming.</li>
          <li>Fix duplicated entries in Windows Program and Features for the Airtame App.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <!-- appstream won't accept a date without a day: https://github.com/ximion/appstream/issues/245 -->
    <release version="3.5.0" date="2019-07-01">
      <description>
        <p>New features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>mDNS discovery support on Windows, Mac and Linux. Chromebook support will be added later.</li>
          <li>Application now automatically sets time and date to Airtame during the setup. It will help to connect Airtame that has no NTP connection to Airtame Cloud</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Issues fixed:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Soundflower rework. Improved installation logic, to accommodate macOS security</li>
          <li>Manual mode rework. Only the next streaming session will be in manual mode now. If you want to always stream in manual mode, there is a trigger for that.</li>
          <li>Linux improvements. Application will install from snap package.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Important bug fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Windows update now handles UAC requests properly</li>
          <li>Fixed SSDP issues when other service would get hold of port 1900</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug when stale out-of-the-box devices were not removed from Airtame device list</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug when launch on start worked only after second reboot on Windows</li>
          <li>Guest application will now only ask for Firewall permissions once</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug when it was impossible to re-setup encrypted device via manual setup flow</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug when 2.4 network sometime would not show in the networks list if there is 5.2 network with the same name</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Others:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>SSDP packets TTL value is now 255. Should make it easier to send discovery packets across multiple VLANs</li>
          <li>"Ignore certificate error" option was added to settings. If you have internal dashboard with insecure certificate set as digital signage, new Airtame browser won't show it because of security settings. To bypass, use the option in the settings.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.3.2" date="2018-12-05">
      <description>
        <p>Issues fixed:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Better support for touch interface (for example Windows Tablet PC's).</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  ​<launchable type="desktop-id">com.airtame.Client.desktop</launchable>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <update_contact>kristian_at_klausen.dk</update_contact>
</component>
